



PROFILE

A London-based senior strategist with over two decades' experience working for some of the world's most successful brands & agencies. Straddling multiple industries, my work focuses on uncovering consumer attitudes, motivations & needs &, in turn, using these insights to identify & decode emergent behavioural shifts that are harnessed to drive & enrich cultural relevancy for businesses & brands. I'm equally at home helping a brand define its point of view & purpose, understanding how to connect with emerging cultures or creating new products, services, content & experiences that engage with your audience. EU national with the right to live & work in the UK.

KEY SKILLS

- Helping brands respond to changing audience habits, market trends & industry disruption
- Unearthing human truths, behaviours, motivations & tensions
- Applying innovative & analytical thinking to solve complex business & marketing issues
- Developing unique & ownable strategic points of view that drive cultural capital & brand relevancy
- Being plugged in & on the leading edge of global brand, cultural & macro consumer trends
- Translating data & the world into meaningful insights & actionable recommendations
- Inspiring people & clients with new thinking, strategic leadership, & creative delivery

CORE COMPETENCES

- Client servicing & business development
- Devising & maintaining budgets and schedules
- Research, strategy, branding, cultural insights & journalism
- Creative outputs and content (video, print, digital, events)
- Stakeholder & internal team engagement initiatives/programmes/workshops
- Leading, managing & inspiring a team and supporting & mentoring junior colleagues

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

Senior Strategist Hunter Design (6-month contract)

 Supporting the Strategy Director, Leadership Team and account groups in providing good counsel across their client base and new business drive, explicitly leading/helping the strategic input on pitches and preparing inspiring creative briefs and strategic ideas for the creative process.

Senior Strategist FutureBrand (6-month contract)

 Combining insight, strategy and design to develop focused creative work rooted in culturally appropriate behaviours to deliver more connected brand experiences and brand strategy projects (i.e. positioning, architecture, naming, design and activation) across multiple industries and brands.

Senior Strategist Freemavens (1-year contract)

Uncovering human insights and revelations by analysing 'real world' data across social, search and other web and digital media –
what consumers are searching for, talking about and sharing in natural unprompted contexts for Pernod Ricard, Coca-Cola and

DECEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2020

Freelance Cultural Insight & Brand Strategy Director

- Creating strategically-led, meaningful partnerships, content strategies, activations and campaigns between artists and brands at Universal Music Group.
- Delivering high-quality brands and culture experiences, communications and content, campaigns, journalism, events, and digital and film projects for Winkrative, Forpeople, Fitch, YourStudio and FutureBrand.

JANUARY 2016 - DECEMBER 2017

Head of Strategic Insights Portland Design

Headed Portland's Strategic Insights Unit that delivered tailored consumer insights and trends research for the retail, travel and leisure industries.

Led a team of strategists, researchers and trend forecasters to future proof brands and businesses using foresight and trends as a catalyst for innovation and future growth.

Advised retailers, airports, commercial property developers and brands on how to shape their retail environments to meet emerging consumer needs and industry innovation.

Organised and hosted Wake-Up Call Seminar breakfast event investigating changes and challenges for the food and beverage industry.

FEBRUARY 2014 - DECEMBER 2016

Strategic Insight Manager Somo

Producing audits, connected world solutions and mobile strategies for Audi, Adidas, Hive, Goldman Sachs, Office shoes and Shop Direct, amongst others.

DECEMBER 2009 - FEBRUARY 2014

Research, Strategy & Planning Consultant

While working as consultant, I also taught as a visiting Lecturer at UEL (University of East London) on second and third-year BA (Hons) Fashion Futures Trend Prediction and Forecasting degree course.

JANUARY 2008 - DECEMBER 2009

Associate Director 2CV Research

Spearheaded global projects with Nokia - from the inspiration stage to helping to steer and refine the industrial design to understanding consumer responses to new products.

JUNE 2007 - JANUARY 2008

Senior Planner VML

Delivered impactful, business-winning creative briefs, digital campaigns and activations.

JUNE 2004 - JUNE 2007

Strategist Naked Communications

Conceived and launched the Music Recommenders.com music service for Nokia Nseries which was aimed at helping music fans stay up to date with new trends and discover new artists.

AUGUST 2000 - JULY 2004

Research Executive Informer Brand Development

Managed the research and production for Informer's leading flagship product the 'Youth Monitor' – the largest on-going qualitative research and marketing study focusing on the lifestyles, attitudes, trends and aspirations of young people in the UK.

SEPTEMBER 1997 - AUGUST 2000

Journalist

Music writer for Amazon.co.uk, The Face, Straight No Chaser, Muzik, Ministry, Flipside, Dazed & Confused, MixMag, Hip Hop Connection and Touch magazines

EDUCATION & TRAINING

2006

Line Manager Training

2005

IPA (Institute of Advertising Practitioners)
Foundation Certificate (Distinction)

1993 - 1990

Liverpool John Moores University: 2.1 BA (Joint Honours), Media and Cultural Studies/Journalism

1991 - 1993

Kingsway College and College of Northeast London. A-Levels: Media Studies (B) Film Studies (B) and City & Guilds Radio and Print Journalism (Distinction)

1985 - 1990

Cardinal Pole School, London. 10 GCSEs: A-C